Anthony Drake

Avon, IN

GitHub: github.com/t27duck LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/t27duck

Twitter: @t27duck Website: t27duck.com

Over **10 years** of professional experience developing web sites and web applications both in a team environment and working alone. I am a strong believer in doing things right the first time and striving for obtainable **long term goals** rather than short term gains via gut reactions. The thrill of using programming to **solve problems** with creative solutions is what I enjoy most about my career.

Skills and Expertise

Proficient Knowledgeable **Used Previously** PHP Ruby (1.9 and 2.x) Sinatra Git Ruby on Rails Redis MySQL Adobe ColdFusion macOS / OSX **PostgreSQL** MiniTest Apache Microsoft Office Suite Visual Basic 6 ¡Query + JavaScript Linux (CentOS, Arch) HTML + CSS **NGINX**

Experience

MOBI (mobiwm.com)

Senior Web Developer

June 2011 - Present

Technologies Used: Ruby on Rails, ¡Query, PostgreSQL, NGINX, Redis, memcached, Solr

- Helped design and implement custom web reporting framework and related features
- Implemented method to allow the importation and manipulation of large amounts of raw mobile carrier data for bill optimization and error detection
- Implemented process of importing client employee information for later use
- Lead major project to upgrade core application to latest Rails and Ruby version
- Mentored developers regarding technical and architectural questions and promoted best practices
- Worked closely with team leads to help promote cross-team collaboration

GoNintendo.com / GoingSony.com Web Developer, Server Admin Oct 2006 – Present Technologies Used (Current): Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, NGINX, Redis, memcahed, Bootstrap Technologies Used (Defunct): PHP, MySQL, lighttpd

- Migrated disjoined WordPress and phpBB site into a unified, custom built PHP site (July 2011)
- Rebuilt site and migrated from PHP / MySQL to Ruby on Rails / PostgreSQL (May 2015)
- Implemented mobile-friendly custom story authoring and commenting system
- Maintains and updates existing web server running CentOS

Bluefish Wireless, Inc.

Web Developer

April 2008 - June 2011

Technologies Used: Adobe ColdFusion, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, jQuery, Prototype

- Built and maintained fully customized web ordering and reporting client web portals
- Maintain and improved internal CRM and order ticketing system
- Built internal IT change request system
- Built configurable e-commerce portal in partnership with Sprint™

Drake Web Development

Owner, Web Developer

June 2006 - June 2008

Technologies Used: PHP, MySQL, Apache

- Web developer freelancer
- Created and maintained the websites for six small business owners

Kroger

U-SCAN operator, Cashier June 2002 – July 2008

- Provided fast and courteous customer service
- Received Service+ award on multiple occasions

Education

Indiana University-Purdue University at Indianapolis

2005 - 2009

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Technology, Web Development

- James D. Bercaw Distinguished Technology Student Award (April 2009 Recipient)
- IUPUI Gamers Guild Webmaster (2006-2009)

Side Projects

active reporting

https://github.com/t27duck/active_reporting

A Ruby gem that implements Relational Online Analytical Processing (ROLAP) features and terminology on top of the ActiveRecord API.

has config

https://github.com/t27duck/has_config

A Ruby gem for record-specific configuration within ActiveRecord models.

Porygon

https://github.com/t27duck/porygon

An IRC bot built for the GoNintendo and GoingSony chatrooms using the chinch gem. Includes a companion Rails 5 application for log viewing and some configuration.

Mallard

https://github.com/t27duck/mallard

A self-hosted, single-user web RSS reader using Sinatra.

jQuery.naw

https://github.com/t27duck/jquery.naw

Not **A W**YSIWYG - A light weight and flexible jQuery plugin for editing content in a HTML text area.

Presentations

Reporting on Rails - ActiveRecord and ROLAP Working Together

RailsConf 2017

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MczzCfTQGfU

Arbitrary Multi-Tenant Configuration for Fun and Profit

Indy.RB Sept 2017

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U_u2w7qNRWg